<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Will Millar</title>
 <link href="http://willmillar.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://willmillar.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-05-28T00:17:36-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://willmillar.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Will Millar</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Bad enterprise experiences: Where do they come from?</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/bad-enterprise-experiences"/>
   <updated>2014-05-28T00:13:07-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/bad-enterprise-experiences</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Khoi Vinh, from his 2007 post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subtraction.com/2007/10/19/if-it-looks-/&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If It Looks Like a Cow, Swims Like a Dolphin and Quacks Like a Duck, It Must Be Enterprise Software&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shielded away from the bright scrutiny of the consumer marketplace and beholden only to a relatively small coterie of information technology managers who are concerned primarily with stability, security and the continual justification of their jobs and staffs, enterprise software answers to few actual users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Discovered via Rachel Kaplowitz&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugeinc.com/ideas/report/ux-in-the-enterprise&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;UX in the Enterprise: Building Software People Actually Use&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for Huge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Indie web philosphy: Why I want to own my content</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/blog/2014/05/27/1-indie-web/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-27T22:06:16-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/blog/2014/05/27/1-indie-web</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think at this point, everyone knows how much I love &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and various other online services&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ghost in the Shell & existential questions of identity</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/ghost-shell"/>
   <updated>2014-05-27T21:36:12-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/3-ghost-in-the-shell</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Major Kusanagi: You talk about redefining my identity. I want a guarantee that I can still be myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puppet Master: There isn&amp;rsquo;t one. Why would you wish to? All things change in a dynamic environment. Your effort to remain what you are is what limits you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell&lt;/em&gt; again for the first time in 10 years and found it much more satisfying. As a teenager, I thought the philosophical themes were &amp;ldquo;really cool,&amp;rdquo; but now I find them worthy of deep thought and serious reflection. I was amazed at how the film uses artificial intelligence and hyper gendered cyborgs to ask questions about the differences between cognition and human life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/wgkaZcq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where does the newborn go from here? The net is vast and infinite.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure I have a face and voice to distinguish myself from others, but my thoughts and memories are unique only to me, and I carry a sense of my own destiny. Each of those things are just a small part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that blends to create a mixture that forms me and gives rise to my conscience. I feel confined, only free to expand myself within boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Major Kusanagi&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- 
Face smash gif: http://i.imgur.com/rqofxcS.gif
Body ripping gif: http://i.imgur.com/JPHEE41.gif
 --&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designers should be using both iOS and Android daily</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/daily-android-use"/>
   <updated>2014-05-27T21:08:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/2-designers-using-android-ios</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Designing for mobile without understanding Android design is as bad as designing a reponsive site without understanding mobile design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A designer needs to keep up with best practices. Best practices aren’t just on one platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve become a better designer because I have learned to see what the best of both systems offers (and worst practices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only using one platform and not the other makes it hard on a designer to learn new design patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Michael Surtees&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Information overload: How much are we really learning?</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/info-overload"/>
   <updated>2014-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/info-overload</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Image via Jennifer Daniel from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re either the smartest or the dumbest we&amp;rsquo;ve ever been. Karl Taro Greenfield on &amp;ldquo;Faking Cultural Literacy&amp;rdquo; in his &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; op-ed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never been so easy to pretend to know so much without actually knowing anything.&lt;/strong&gt; We pick topical, relevant bits from Facebook, Twitter or emailed news alerts, and then regurgitate them&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What matters to us, awash in petabytes of data, is not necessarily having actually consumed this content firsthand but simply knowing that it exists — and having a position on it, being able to engage in the chatter about it. &lt;strong&gt;We come perilously close to performing a pastiche of knowledgeability that is really a new model of know-nothingness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brilliant and terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designing down and building up</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/blog/2014/05/22/designvelopment/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-22T18:48:49-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/blog/2014/05/22/designvelopment</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; starting with &amp;ldquo;Hello world&amp;rdquo; and building up was so much different than starting with a final mockup and building down&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Building willmillar.com 4.0 with Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/building-the-site"/>
   <updated>2014-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/building-the-site</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Goodbye CMS! The new willmillar.com is built with code using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. This means I can design from sketches instead of starting from someone else&amp;rsquo;s page templates. Divorcing the content from design was a very powerful change, and I had a great time getting back into code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Designing in code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Design tools&amp;rdquo; have been defined to me as the page layout programs like InDesign, OmniGraffle, Photoshop, Sketch. These are great for preliminary high-level concepting, but I often find them to be a significant hindrance once your high-level design system is set. I was really excited for a design project where I can &lt;strong&gt;ditch static comps early in the process&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll processes my posts into the templates I designed with HTML and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt;. This is ideal for my writing workflow because I can write in human-readable &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; in any text editor. No HTML tags to muck up the prose, and no stupid CMS WYSIWYG text editor to fight with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process improved my writing, workflow, and throughput. And it was fun and I learned a lot! The site built from &lt;a href=&quot;http://demo.getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; with typography from &lt;a href=&quot;https://typekit.com/&quot;&gt;Typekit&lt;/a&gt;. No extra plugins or hidden gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not technically responsive, the site uses &lt;strong&gt;single-column design&lt;/strong&gt; with a few media queries to render a speedy and attractive experience on almost any device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/willmillar-com-4-0-graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Commits to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/willmillar/willmillar.github.io&quot;&gt;willmillar.github.io&lt;/a&gt; repo over the six weeks of spare time it took to learn Jekyll and Liquid, design and build the site, and write the content&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting started was the hardest part&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge in the process was getting the plane off the ground! I had whipped up some designs in OmniGraffle for a new site late one night. They sat on my desktop for a couple weeks while I looked into WYSIWYG-style CMSs like SquareSpace, new blogging engines like &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, and traditional CMS systems like Wordpress. Eventually, I decided on Jekyll:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll made me get my hands dirty with code.&lt;/strong&gt; Given my hangups with the traditional design process of developing detailed mockups, I figured I should try a project where I design in code to see if the grass is really greener. It&amp;rsquo;s time to eat my own dogfood, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working in code gives a designer superpowers.&lt;/strong&gt; Every layer of abstraction is a layer of control that you give up as a designer. This is not to say that high-level design tools make poor designs, but they should be considered as limited. Conducting the ebb and flow of a live site is a much different skill than making a polished static mockup. My experience has found code skills to be more relevant and reusable for a web designer than being really good at Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It looks like Jekyll is here to stay&lt;/strong&gt; (at least for a while). &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; uses Jekyll, and there is a very active community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Inspiration &amp;amp; references&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/digital-product-design/a44f802fee11&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Refuse to Create a UX Portfolio&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Timothy Gaeger via Medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portfolios, blogs, personal sites I referenced: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jonwiley.com/index.html&quot;&gt;jonwiley.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marco.org/&quot;&gt;marco.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/&quot;&gt;daringfireball.net&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://veen.com/jeff/&quot;&gt;veen.com/jeff&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://adactio.com/&quot;&gt;adactio.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://markdotto.com/&quot;&gt;markdotto.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffvlahos.com/&quot;&gt;jeffvlahos.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;http://nathanhass.com/&quot;&gt;nathanhass.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jpboneyard.com/&quot;&gt;jpboneyard.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://emilybrick.me/&quot;&gt;emilybrick.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Also thanks to my friends and colleagues for their input during the design process!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Experience design consulting</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/experience-design-consulting"/>
   <updated>2014-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/experience-design-consulting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am currently an Experience Designer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sapient.com/en-us/sapientnitro.html&quot; title=&quot;SapientNitro.com&quot;&gt;SapientNitro&lt;/a&gt; where I research and sketch to design prototypes for large-scale websites. A portfolio of select deliverables is available by request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Panera Bread&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SapientNitro works closely with &lt;a title=&quot;PaneraBread.com&quot; href=&quot;https://www.panerabread.com/&quot;&gt;Panera Bread&lt;/a&gt; for their web presence and digital ordering experience across desktop, mobile, and in-store. I was the lead user experience designer for several projects &lt;strong&gt;defining key ordering flows including check out and order setup&lt;/strong&gt;. We introduced design systems which tested better with users and were easier to build and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Analog Devices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SapientNitro recently worked with semiconductor manufacturer &lt;a title=&quot;Analog.com&quot; href=&quot;http://www.analog.com/&quot;&gt;Analog Devices,&lt;/a&gt; who will be launching a large redesign later this year. On the UX team, we &lt;strong&gt;defined the design system&lt;/strong&gt; while working closely with the client to understand the business, with strategists to understand electrical enginners, and with business analysis to define requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;AlzForum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, SapientNitro worked with Fidelity Biosciences to redesign &lt;a title=&quot;AlzForum.org&quot; href=&quot;http://alzforum.org/&quot;&gt;AlzForum.org&lt;/a&gt;. The organization was moving to Drupal to offer a cross-platform experience for their users and a more reliable interface for their editors. As a UX designer, I &lt;strong&gt;supported the design system, defined detailed interactions, and led the editor documentation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Our education system is outdated, not necessarily broken</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/outdated-education"/>
   <updated>2014-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/outdated-education-system</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sugata Mitra, Professor of Educational Technology at Newcastle University, from his TED talk &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/sugata_mitra_build_a_school_in_the_cloud&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Build a School in the Cloud&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you look at present-day schooling the way it is, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to figure out where it came from&amp;hellip; Imagine trying to run the show, trying to run the entire planet, without computers, without telephones, with data handwritten on pieces of paper, and traveling by ships&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They created a global computer made up of people. It&amp;rsquo;s still with us today. It&amp;rsquo;s called the bureaucratic administrative machine. In order to have that machine running, you need lots and lots of people. They made another machine to produce those people: the school. The schools would produce the people who would then become parts of the bureaucratic administrative machine. They must be identical to each other. They must know three things: They must have good handwriting, because the data is handwritten; they must be able to read; and they must be able to do multiplication, division, addition and subtraction in their head&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The empire is gone, so what are we doing with that design that produces these identical people, and what are we going to do next if we ever are going to do anything else with it? Schools as we know them are obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly where my head was at when I was &lt;a href=&quot;/gather&quot;&gt;thinking about digital learning platforms&lt;/a&gt; at MassArt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Heard on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ted.com/2013/05/03/ted-radio-hour-presents-unstoppable-learning/&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unstoppable Learning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;NPR&amp;rsquo;s TED Radio Hour&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Interaction Design (CDGD 330) Syllabus</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/ixd-course"/>
   <updated>2013-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/interaction-design-course</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Basics in user-centered design, concepts, methodologies, and tools. Site mapping, wireframing, user personas, and flows for effective, innovative experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:willmillar@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Will Millar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Meeting time:&lt;/strong&gt; Tuesdays, 6:30–10:00 PM, Tower 629&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See Also:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schoology.com/page/59652379&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tentative Course Schedule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schoology.com/page/59652657&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Course Policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi and welcome to CDGD 330: Interaction Design!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course seeks to provide an introduction to current concepts, methods, and technologies employed in the design of interactive media. Subjects of study include defining user and site requirements, managing information complexity, and designing visual interfaces that are usable and testable. Assignments address design problem solving within screen-based projects developed for various content, needs, and audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be &lt;strong&gt;working together in a professional context on &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; projects.&lt;/strong&gt; These projects will help &lt;strong&gt;familiarize students with industry practices and deliverables,&lt;/strong&gt; as well as work through the fundamental concepts of &lt;em&gt;interaction design, usability, experience design, information architecture,&lt;/em&gt; and the various methodologies that support said disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lecture&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(30–90 minutes)&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topical discussion of Theory and Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio Critique&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1–3 hours)&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5–20 minutes per student&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student presents weekly progress on all deliverables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Class provides feedback on updated work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I expect the course become more critique-focused and less lecture-focused over the semester as we dig deeper into project work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Questions Answered&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What makes a digital service great?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What happens when you click?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What happens in a user&amp;rsquo;s mind?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you organize information logically and usably?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you effectively render intent?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Course Topics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research&lt;/strong&gt; (Discovery)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience Design&lt;/strong&gt; (Prototyping)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/strong&gt; (Planning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Interface&lt;/strong&gt; (Visual Design)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methodology&lt;/strong&gt; (Practices)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Text and Required Supplies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sensible.com/dmmt.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t Make Me Think: A Common Sense Approach to Web Usability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Available as eBook from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/15a5Uh6&quot;&gt;iBooks ($16)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/15a60VW&quot;&gt;Kindle ($16)&lt;/a&gt;; or paperback from &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1aFAMOD&quot;&gt;Amazon ($25)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schoology.com/course/59421575/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schoology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course materials and reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syllabus, Policies, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course schedule and due dates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submission of Assigments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Google Drive documents will be listed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign Up:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schoology.com/&quot;&gt;schoology.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Click Sign Up (or Log In if you already have an account)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Select &amp;ldquo;Student&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Enter the following Access Code: &lt;strong&gt;CM35R-5CWMC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/folderview?id=0B_u2W625O4GkSzJsLXhDcFNnRkk&amp;amp;usp=sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Drive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(formerly Google Docs)&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repository of updated class resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Course Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience Shift&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Redesign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Futurecasting Product/Service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Notes: &ldquo;What Clients Don&rsquo;t Know and Why It&rsquo;s Your Fault&rdquo; with Mike Monteiro</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/aea-monteiro"/>
   <updated>2013-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/aea-mike-monteiro</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mike Monteiro of Mule Design and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVkLVRt6c1U&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fuck You Pay Me&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; on the role of designers and empathy for our clients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[As a designer] you&amp;rsquo;re going to spend 90% of your time convincing people that the shit you thought of in the shower is right.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;From his talk &amp;ldquo;What Client&amp;rsquo;s Don&amp;rsquo;t Know and Why It&amp;rsquo;s Your Fault&amp;rdquo; at An Event Apart Boston 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;These ideas are only as good as you are at going back to your job and selling them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you are a designer, you are always convincing someone of something.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need to take more responsibility for how you do your job.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;You cannot put the onus of your job on someone else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Express empathy with your expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Designers, you are in the service industry!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be that grumpy, rude clerk who waists his expertise on his lack of empathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client service: Don&amp;rsquo;t be irritated — be empathetic!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making things is the easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re going to spend 90% of your time convincing people that the shit you though of in the shower is right.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;If it helps you do your job, it&amp;rsquo;s part of your job&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The designer-client relationship is not at all a teacher-student relationship

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn enough about each others&#39; businesses that you can successfully work together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not take on clients you don&amp;rsquo;t respect because you can&amp;rsquo;t empathize with those you don&amp;rsquo;t respect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clients don&amp;rsquo;t know when to get a designer involved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Eye-rolling is not a design skill.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;As long as you insist on acting like a disenfranchised creative, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly how you deserve to be treated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stop waiting for an invitation to do your job&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The work does not speak for itself&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell your service, not your work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for the problem that you solved and &lt;strong&gt;use your work as a prop to illustrate the idea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients don&amp;rsquo;t know the best way to evaluate a designer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clients and designers find each other via referrals&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Referrals are the most precious commodity we have.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every job you do is a sales pitch for the next job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goods RFPs &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; exist!

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parts

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The solution comes from working together, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; from an RFP

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;RFPs may be a client&amp;rsquo;s way to tell you they&amp;rsquo;re scared&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work together to establish solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you help write the RFP, you&amp;rsquo;re in an even better position to get the work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help clients define a process that works well for both sides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RFPs are just another design problem to solve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just answer your client&amp;rsquo;s questions, figure out why they&amp;rsquo;re asking those questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never work for someone you can&amp;rsquo;t argue with&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never work from somebody you can&amp;rsquo;t say &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t make your pricing a secret. Make it a datapoint.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your process is a mystery to most clients&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can you do to demystify design process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;on you&lt;/em&gt; to help your clients understand your process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do everything in your power to be right, but never be afraid to be wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you say &amp;ldquo;The client doesn&amp;rsquo;t get it,&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;re saying &amp;ldquo;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to get my point across&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everything that is wrong with design today is your fault.&amp;rdquo; And that is good news, because it&amp;rsquo;s your job to fix it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Notes: &ldquo;Silo-Busting with Scenarios&rdquo; with Kim Goodwin</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/aea-goodwin"/>
   <updated>2013-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/aea-kim-goodwin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kim Goodwin, VP of UX at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patientslikeme.com/&quot;&gt;Patients Like Me&lt;/a&gt;, former VP of UX at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cooper.com/&quot;&gt;Cooper&lt;/a&gt; on how &amp;ldquo;silos have been engineered to ignore one another&amp;rdquo; and scenarios help designers and organizations &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;define problems as your users do&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;From her talk &amp;ldquo;Silo-Busting with Scenarios&amp;rdquo; at An Event Apart Boston 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Silos have been engineered to ignore one another&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dangerous ideas are &amp;ldquo;contained&amp;rdquo; inside of silos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining problems within silos mean that solutions have to be narrow

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to solve problems from a holistic user scenario level, rather than within your organization&amp;rsquo;s silos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users are aware of the gaps between silos and land users in &lt;strong&gt;UX purgatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best user experiences come from ignoring organizational silos

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod won the market because it was designed for the whole ecosystem, not for discrete user actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A set of scenarios is a great tool to ignore silos&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;A plausible future story that stars a persona&amp;rdquo; who solves a problem on their terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Solve for &lt;em&gt;people,&lt;/em&gt; not &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Express users as characters that &lt;em&gt;we care about&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Wall-E is a robot, but is relatable because he has dreams, weaknesses, and personality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real humans have a range of needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good design processes oscillate between &amp;ldquo;Generative&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Analytical&amp;rdquo; states&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What could we do that would be awesome?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytical&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scenarios can be used from the beginning of the design process on

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product definition all the way through to detailed visual design and implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you get to a good scenario?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starts with user research&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Forget what &lt;em&gt;you&amp;rsquo;re&lt;/em&gt; building&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead, listen to the person and understand how they see the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define your problem at your users&#39; level (&amp;ldquo;I want a better travel experience&amp;rdquo;) not at the level of your organization (&amp;ldquo;I want a new flight-booking system&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask specific questions (&amp;ldquo;Tell me about your last routine trip&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;Tell me about your last trip&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have your user go through their current scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your users feelings along the way?&lt;/strong&gt; What experiences make you gripe? What experiences make you cheer?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make scenarios by &amp;ldquo;unsucking&amp;rdquo; the bad experiences?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce effort, anxiety, friction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We want to make experiences delightful, not just usable!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add something unexpectedly Good&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask &amp;ldquo;What would a helpful human do?&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Imagine that your user has a proactive, smart assistant&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delight your users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make it a story&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Written prose optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep user&amp;rsquo;s emotional state front and center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrates users&#39; needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss and decide&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How much of this is behind bars, how much is worth investigating, and how much do we know we can do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[!] &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;If the stakeholders said yes to everything, you didn&amp;rsquo;t push far enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look at your silo informed by the bigger journey&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never forget to put your ideas in the context of the entire user journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick several small&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use incredibly low-fidelity storyboarding to articulate&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumbnails — don&amp;rsquo;t worry about the details — think about &lt;em&gt;structure&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;flow&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The sequence of the UI layout is defined by the sequence of the scenario&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about navigation from the outset

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype out the flows, look for commonalities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritize functionality as you identify opportunities for convergence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top-level IA emerges from prototyping through scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss and decide&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop roadmap to map out when certain functionaries are eligible for implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polish the details&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scenarios work all the way down to the details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask what will other personas not understand? What will they need changed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual hierarchy

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interaction designer can say &amp;ldquo;this is not emphasizing XYZ correctly&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows interaction designers to articulate need, but visual designer to create an original solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Scenarios are my &amp;lsquo;desert-island&amp;rsquo; design tool&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Define problems as your users do&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good things happen only when all team members who are responsible for &lt;em&gt;a part of the experience&lt;/em&gt; take responsibility for &lt;em&gt;the whole experience.&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your job isn&amp;rsquo;t to &amp;ldquo;do UX&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;code a website.&amp;rdquo; Your job is to work to provide users with delightful experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Notes: &ldquo;The Mobile Content Mandate&rdquo; with Karen McGrane</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/aea-goodwin"/>
   <updated>2013-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/aea-karen-mcgrane</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Karen McGrane, author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/content-strategy-for-mobile&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Content Strategy for Mobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on why &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as &amp;lsquo;how to write for mobile.&amp;rsquo; There&amp;rsquo;s just good writing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;From her talk &amp;ldquo;The Mobile Content Mandate&amp;rdquo; at An Event Apart Boston 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scarcity of computing affects what people do and make with technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no reason anyone will need to to &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; on mobile&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is like saying &amp;ldquo;No one will ever want a computer in &lt;em&gt;their home&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clayton Christensen&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Theory Disruptive Innovation&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In industry after industry, the new technologies that brought the big established companies to their knees weren&amp;rsquo;t better or more&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D.E.C. had its lunch eaten by the personal computer market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These products only do &lt;strong&gt;one thing well&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They create a new vertical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the technology into the hands of people who have never had access to it before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radios, Printing, Photography industries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mobile devices are the new personal computers&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPhone is not a fancy cell phone — &amp;ldquo;it is a really cheap computer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Digital Divide

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% of Americans have no internet access at all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35% of Americans have no internet access at home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;38% of low income no internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;59% of low income no broadband&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile ownership 88% (2012)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile internet use 55% (2012)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of those, 31% claim they only or mostly use the internet on mobile

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more than IE9 users, more than the amount of people with JavaScript turned off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mobile has erased the digital divide. A mobile device is the internet for many people&amp;rdquo; —Susannah Fox, Pew Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 16% of consumer brands have a mobile strategy (Digiday)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 20% of B2B brands have a mobile strategy (Business Publishing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Mobile sites&amp;rsquo; are a crutch that have gotten us through the past five years&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mobile users are not second class citizens&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not everyone will go to your &amp;ldquo;real website.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;For many users, the mobile site &lt;em&gt;is the real site&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Strategy for Mobile

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &lt;em&gt;Content Strategy for Mobile&lt;/em&gt; for A Book Apart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actionable steps

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Understand the workflows for content creation and publishing in your organization

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time to make the content!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web and mobile teams should not be siloed!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So much of the time, the mobile site is &lt;em&gt;better,&lt;/em&gt; so why isn&amp;rsquo;t it the website for everyone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Write better. You can do this right now.&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as &amp;lsquo;how to write for mobile.&amp;rsquo; There&amp;rsquo;s just good writing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less jargon, declarative sentences, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case study: &lt;em&gt;American Cancer Society&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good content transcends platform.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile is a good chance to clean up your crappy content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Chunk your content appropriately

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Chunk your blobs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which content should we include or exclude?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should long pages be broken into shorter ones?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will it work to reuse headings as links?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will it work to truncate body copy for teasers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What fallbacks can we provide if our desktop content fails?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Responsive design won&amp;rsquo;t fix your content problem.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A package of image crops

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you do this for text?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truncating headlines is just wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &amp;ldquo;Guardian Truncation Team&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write shorter versions of headlines?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Length:&lt;/strong&gt; 60 characters, 100 characters, 200 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tone &amp;amp; style:&lt;/strong&gt; SEO-optimized, colloquial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superheads and subheads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write multiple redundant versions of copy to avoid constant truncation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to provide enough context for users to confidently make a decision and not worry that they are going down the wrong path

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comcast uses subtext under headlines to help provide context to users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t create content for a specific context. Think about it as a flexible, reusable system. You don&amp;rsquo;t get to decide which device people use to access your content. They do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Notes: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a Great Time to be an Experience Designer&rdquo; with Jared Spool</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/aea-spool"/>
   <updated>2013-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/aea-jared-spool</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jared Spool of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uie.com/&quot;&gt;UIE&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://centercentre.com/&quot;&gt;Center Centre&lt;/a&gt; on how the skills that define the &lt;strong&gt;best designers&lt;/strong&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;storytelling, critiquing, sketching, presenting, and facilitating&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;From his talk &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a Great Time to Be an Experience Designer&amp;rdquo; at An Event Apart Boston 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why does everyone want to copy the Apple Store?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything in the Apple Store is &lt;em&gt;intentionally designed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design is &lt;em&gt;the rendering of intent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imitation&lt;/em&gt; is far less expensive and risky than &lt;em&gt;Innovation&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imitation views design as a &lt;strong&gt;commodity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovation views design as a &lt;strong&gt;competitive advantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Businesses win when they are intentionally innovative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I move things around until they look right.&amp;rdquo; —Milton Glaser&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But design is about the &lt;em&gt;business,&lt;/em&gt; not just the &lt;em&gt;visual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great business models are intentionally designed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business needs designers &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Map customer journeys on an axis of their emotions :) →:(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Innovation is not about adding new inventions, it&amp;rsquo;s about adding new value”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiences should be mapped, measured, and designed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience design: the rendering of intent within the gaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150k job listings for UX design in the US&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What skills are found among the best design teams?&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience Design

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Process Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Research Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interaction Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Design (about clear communication)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing &amp;amp; Curating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethnographic Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain Knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What separates out &lt;em&gt;the best&lt;/em&gt; designers?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critiquing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sketching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facilitating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Innovation is saying &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to a thousand ideas before saying &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rise of the UX generalist&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialist:&lt;/strong&gt; Having more expertise in one area over others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generalist:&lt;/strong&gt; Having equal expertise in most areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compartmentalist:&lt;/strong&gt; Having expertise in &lt;em&gt;only one&lt;/em&gt; area (a career-limiting decision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being a specialist isn&amp;rsquo;t about having the desire to specialize, it&amp;rsquo;s just finding a job that pays you to work only in that narrow field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UX generalists need all of the skills listed above

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some claim that Experience Designers are Unicorns that don&amp;rsquo;t exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to become a Design Unicorn:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train yourself

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read and learn everything there is to know about a skill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn the vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice your skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deconstruct as many good designs as you can&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek out feedback (and listen to it!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach others

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to take the things you&amp;rsquo;ve internalized and &lt;em&gt;externalize&lt;/em&gt; them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great experiences provide a competitive return on investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teams need generalists more than specialists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unicorns exist! You can become one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Design Career Primer</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/design-careers"/>
   <updated>2013-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/design-career-primer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since graduating MassArt, I get semi-regular requests for &lt;strong&gt;advice to design students looking to get traction in the professional world&lt;/strong&gt;. I love to meet with other young designers, but I also wanted to summarize what knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up so far to younger students to helpfully improve understanding of their professional possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried writing single-paragraph templated advice, but mostly became a whitewash of generic careerisms (&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theonion.com/articles/find-the-thing-youre-most-passionate-about-then-do,31742/&quot;&gt;what you love&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; etc.&lt;/em&gt;). I&amp;rsquo;ve also gone looking for some sort of overall guide to framing the concepts of design careers, but I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This primer is my attempt to start filling that gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;A warning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that while I have &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; academic and professional design experience, it is not only limited, but also provides notable bias to my perspective on design as a practice, industry, and career. Section &lt;em&gt;IV. Helpful Resources&lt;/em&gt; has some good places to cross-reference anything written here. And if something still smells funny, &lt;a href=&quot;#footer&quot;&gt;call me on it&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Job shopping criteria&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Level of commitment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i.e. &lt;em&gt;In what capacity/on what terms will you be working?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Full-time employment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;40&amp;rdquo; hours per week &lt;em&gt;(read: 30–50 hours per week)&lt;/em&gt;; Salaried&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliable income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relative job security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the company yacht&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unpaid overtime is sometimes considered an industry-wide expectation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highest level of commitment (if you are concerned about the fit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;2. Contract employment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defined engagement with an end-date; Can be salaried or hourly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid by the hour (overtime! woo hoo!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often good pay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less-permanent commitment than full time (if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No benefits (health, life, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be harder to embed oneself in company culture (possible &amp;ldquo;outsider&amp;rdquo; effect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less job security than full-time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All taxes come out of &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; paycheck, so you can take home significantly less after taxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;3. Freelance employment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-employed arrangement; Salaried or hourly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You pick the clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have the talent, experience, and business skills, you stand to make significantly more money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting good, real clients is seriously hard (though a worthwhile effort)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you are freelancing on or with a team, you likely have &lt;strong&gt;no one to learn from,&lt;/strong&gt; which is not optimal early on in your career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like contract work, you pay your own taxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;4. Internship employment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defined engagement, often with an end date; Usually hourly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-down best way to gain experience, make connections, and impress employers without any level of commitment (don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about being &amp;ldquo;stuck&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can possibly lead to a  long-term engagement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little job security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously, you&amp;rsquo;re the lowest on the totem pole (but that&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;price for experience&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Industry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i.e. &lt;em&gt;What does this company do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not intended to be an all-inclusive list. The following industries are just some popular destinations among recent design graduates. Also, remember that many modern companies aren&amp;rsquo;t easy or possible to categorize into a &lt;em&gt;single&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;industry,&amp;rdquo; and are often reluctant to so, which makes classification all the more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Advertising&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advertising/marketing can be an exciting field to get into. It&amp;rsquo;s quite popular for design graduates for the alluring work, reasonable compensation, and networking/career growth opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invigorating culture; networking opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often large-budget projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;Idea-centered&amp;rsquo; design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cool funtimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great experience across multiple disciplines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often designing artifacts to market &lt;em&gt;other design objects,&lt;/em&gt; rather than designing those products or services themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the shop and project, it can be less creatively stimulating than more &lt;em&gt;heady&lt;/em&gt; types of design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;2. Interactive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design for interactive projects is growing and changing rapidly, and has lots of fascinating opportunities that provide unique challenges, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re able and willing to get your hands dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital continues to be &amp;ldquo;The Thing&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; industry; some of the most cutting-edge world-changing work happens in digital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic media jobs (i.e. web, tools, apps, etc&amp;hellip;) often have higher compensation than designing counterparts for print media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of their large scale, interactive projects are great to stretch your role and get experience outside of your traditional comfort zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often highly complex projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not unlike  print work, digital design processes involve a high level of detail-oriented grind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;3. Print and traditional graphic design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The print design industry is most outside of my professional wheelhouse&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the beautiful, fun, and creative stuff you learned in art school at a super-professional level!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The print industry is slowly but steadily drying up and work is becoming more challenging to find&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;4. Various media client-side&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TV/video, movies, magazines, etc. all have scores of designers working on their products, but from what I understand, this industry can be about knowing people and being able to get to the right locations (New York or LA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexy work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often great for your portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be exciting and fun if in the right organization and role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In line with my comments about freelancing &lt;em&gt;(above)&lt;/em&gt;, working for a non-design-focused company can make it challenging to grow and expand professionally, with less focus on things like research, ideation, and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be pigeonholed as an &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;-designer&amp;rdquo; (i.e. a &amp;lsquo;web banner-designer&amp;rsquo; or a &amp;lsquo;Photoshop-designer&amp;rsquo;) if there is little support for design career growth within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can require additional effort to connect and network with other designers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;5. Other client-side&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all businesses hire designers in one way or another. Many of the largest architecture firms, restaurants, consumer goods manufacturers, fashion and clothing companies, among others, have whole internal, &amp;lsquo;in-house&amp;rsquo; creative teams!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros &amp;amp; Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See&lt;/em&gt; Pros &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/em&gt; Cons &lt;em&gt;above, although in a non-media company, there&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable chance that the work could be less sexy.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/your_mileage_may_vary&quot;&gt;YMMV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Company size&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These distinctions are relatively arbitrary, but it is a helpful framework to conceptualize the size company you would like to be at.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Small company&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be a great way to form close relationships with talented and experienced colleagues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tighter, cohesive working groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More likely to get traction to initiate change within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to maintain high visibility within the company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often easier to expand your role into other disciplines (good way to work your way into becoming a generalist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any &lt;em&gt;personality&lt;/em&gt; or team-related issues can be amplified without all the &amp;lsquo;buffer room&amp;rsquo; present in larger organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While it is quite possible to flourish under the right circumstances, it can also be challenging to maintain professional growth if the organization doesn&amp;rsquo;t have room for your role to expand or change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be scarce on resources (limited IT support, less dedicated resources for things like expenses and office services)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;2. Medium company&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo;-sized organization is a great way to get a mix of the pros and cons of small and large firms &lt;em&gt;(see above and below).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Large company&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Pros:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Likely to work on bigger, more widely-relevant projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More brains to pick (lots of smart people to learn from)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many opportunities to network, grow and learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure to a wide gamut of high-performing specialists in a variety of domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure to multiple styles of leadership, management, and organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Cons:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It could be easy to get lost or remain at a low visibility within the organization (especially with lots of talented individuals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased volume of workers and varied processes have the capacity to increase friction and inhibit progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Role Title&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many college design graduates begin with a &amp;ldquo;Junior&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Intern&amp;rdquo; title, though it is not impossible to land a  mid-level job out of school. And of course titles vary from company to company and there are many variations and misuses of title.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Visual designer / graphic designer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Works with:&lt;/strong&gt; Visuals, typography, layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Photoshop, Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;User experience designer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Works with:&lt;/strong&gt; Prototypes, taxonomies, wireframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential tools:&lt;/strong&gt; InDesign, OmniGraffle, Axure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Art director&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Works with:&lt;/strong&gt; Concepts, styles, directions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Important focus areas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do I get a job?!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously there is no substitute for great work. Doing your best on your project work is the surest way to communicate your employability, and it is always a worthwhile endeavor. That being said, don&amp;rsquo;t let your classwork overrun your ability to develop your &lt;strong&gt;networking&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;soft skills&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. Network&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I understand, most viable job leads come from personal connections. Now this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that you are best friends with someone. This just means that maybe you would recognize this person if you bumped into them at an event. I know plenty of people who got great job leads through various portfolio reviews (popular reviews are run by AIGA, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adcglobal.org/education/portfolio/&quot;&gt;Art Directors&#39; Club&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.behance.net/reviews&quot;&gt;Behance&lt;/a&gt;, among other design groups). Also, follow local design groups (such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aiga.org/chapters/&quot;&gt;your local AIGA chapter&lt;/a&gt;) to get notified of upcoming local design events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Develop &amp;ldquo;soft skills&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put it all in a pretty package! &lt;a href=&quot;http://justcreative.com/2008/10/02/design-elevator-speeches/&quot;&gt;Develop and rehearse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designsponge.com/2009/05/biz-ladies-09-the-30-second-elevator-pitch.html&quot;&gt;an introductory &amp;ldquo;elevator speech&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for yourself and your work. A great presentation with smooth delivery can make up for even a &lt;em&gt;glaring&lt;/em&gt; design error, without much luck required. There is &lt;em&gt;an unbelievable amount&lt;/em&gt; of value in developing your own window-dressing (e.g. speaking and presentation skills, beautiful business cards, being at the right networking events or portfolio reviews, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Learning potential&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most important consideration in finding a great entry-level job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As suggested to me by my former professor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brianlucid.com&quot;&gt;Brian Lucid&lt;/a&gt;, the best thing a first job could have is the opportunity to learn a lot. In a dream world, this comes in the form of mentorship and guidance; smart, talented coworkers with the dedication to promoting learning and growth; and wise leadership to keep it all going in the right direction. Coming out of school, there is no built-in learning network to propel career forward, so having an employer that actively enables your learning and development is truly an excellent benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Helpful resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. Your professors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are, if you had a decent design program, you have some pretty damn great professors! Reach out to them. If they&amp;rsquo;re worth their salt, and you remain respectful (especially to their valuable time), they&amp;rsquo;ll be glad to help. And while they mean well, it&amp;rsquo;s never a bad idea to cross-reference their advice with other professors, as well as any industry professionals to make sure they know what they&amp;rsquo;re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. Your peers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by a bunch of degenerates, the people around you are all doing this stuff too! Take advantage of it! Share contacts and intel (with discretion), share good resources and job listings, consult about opportunities, make a private Facebook group, do it up! Competition only gets in the way as much as you let it. Also, building your professional network (and your LinkedIn!) starts as early as you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Working professionals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably know at least &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; with professional experience in art or design. They are great resources! Send an email or a Facebook message, or better yet offer to take them out for coffee or lunch if it feels comfortable and they can spare the time. Give them a sense of what you are trying to do and then let them give you whatever information they have gained in their experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designsalaries.aiga.org/&quot;&gt;Survey of Design Salaries 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AIGA &amp;amp; Aiquent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incredibly helpful as a general reference in the salary negotiation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aiga.org/interior.aspx?pageid=3079&amp;amp;id=11033&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beyond Craft and Tools: The Skills Design Students Must Master&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;David Shirwin via AIGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent and relatively concise overview of the industry and the best way in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jessicahische.is/thinkingthoughts/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thoughts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jessica Hische&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While occasionally taking a nearly combative tone, Jessica Hische&amp;rsquo;s suggestions to future artists and designers are always well-supported and often spot-on. Her piece, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jessicahische.is/thinkingthoughts/aboutpricing/&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Dark Art of Pricing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, is not to be missed, especially if you are looking into doing freelance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.risdcareers.com/careerresources/handouts--guides/&quot;&gt;RISD Career Resources Guides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RISD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RISD has some pretty fantastic PDFs online that have solid traditional career advice. From cover letter best practices to tips on building your LinkedIn profile, there is a lot of good info to check out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aiga.org/portfolio-presenting/&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Presenting Your Portfolio&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short article by &lt;em&gt;Steff Geissbuhler&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;em&gt;AIGA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linkedin.com&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn is a fabulous source for design job listings! I was quite impressed with the quality on LinkedIn. Try searching by the role that you would like to look at (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/jsearch?type=jobs&amp;amp;search=Search&amp;amp;keywords=junior+designer&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Junior Designer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the talented and inspiring designers I follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lukew&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luke Wroblewski&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — User experience, mobile-first, responsive web design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zeldman&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Arguably &amp;ldquo;The&amp;rdquo; web design guy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@beep&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Responsive web design pioneer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brad_frost&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brad Frost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Web design and development genius&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jessicahische&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jessica Hische&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Freelance illustration, design and typography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kaikkonendesign.fi/the-threshold-after-which-you-should-stop-specializing-and-be-a-generalist/&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Threshold After Which You Should Stop Specializing and Be a Generalist&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short article by &lt;em&gt;Tommi Kaikkonen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Actual Books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/design-is-a-job&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design is a Job&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mikemonteiro.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mike Monteiro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Graphic-Artists-Handbook-Pricing-Guidelines/dp/0932102158/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Handbook of Pricing and Ethical Guidelines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graphic Artist&amp;rsquo;s Guild&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Digital learning platform</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/gather"/>
   <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/gather</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gather&lt;/em&gt; is a concept service which provides a single access point for digital learning in schools. It connects assorted resources and tools to make it easy for teachers to construct their own curriculum in a way that works for students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h6&gt;Challenge&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Classroom education was not built for a connected world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gather-lectures.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Should preparing and delivering a lecture look the same as it did 500 years ago?&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format of classroom education has changed very little in hundreds of years, despite fundamental advances in information infrastructure. The traditional &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;sage on stage&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; lecture format does not account for the fact that information is all around us. In a future where learning is no longer one way, &lt;strong&gt;we are not equipped to facilitate classroom interactions which bring in outside content in an organized yet open manor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Process&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Learning from Blackboard, Salman Khan, and Bruce Mau&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gather-blackboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Are current tools actually enabling the learning process? The education category is plagued by complex and unintuitive interfaces.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Blackboard to Khan Academy, many brilliant minds are trying to crack the future of digital education systems. However, most of these &amp;ldquo;learning management systems&amp;rdquo; are rooted in specific tools, such as a resource manager or assignment tracker. As illustrated above, &lt;strong&gt;these tools are not friendly for teachers or students to learn and use.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw the need for a high-level layer which pulls all these desparate pieces together into a single friendly interface on any device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Mau&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Third Teacher&lt;/em&gt; focuses on the role of the &amp;ldquo;teacher as designer.&amp;rdquo; We need to empower teachers with powerful education design tools to choreograph networks of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Solution&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Give teachers control by unifying learning resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gather-diagrams.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Consolidating the content model gives power and control to teachers&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to a better system for teachers and learners is a unified content service which makes creating your own curriculum by snapping existing resources together. The curriculum materials could then be packaged as a presentation, longform reading, problem set, or test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This gives teachers a single place to plan curriculum, prepare materials, and manage student activity&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for more efficient planning and more customized material. In turn, students could access all materials through any device and seamlessly transition between using an iPad at home, TVs or projectors, and their own mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gather-sketches.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better tools can improve education&lt;/strong&gt; by supercharging the planning process for teachers and giving students access to all materials everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;video&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://player.vimeo.com/video/41698023?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=3a92c9&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;center-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cta&quot; title=&quot;Gather Degree Project Process Book&quot; href=&quot;http://issuu.com/willmillar/docs/dp-process_book-v3-export_hi_pages&quot;&gt;Process book on Issuu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This service was developed as a concept for Jan Kubasiewicz&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Degree Project&lt;/em&gt; course at Massachusetts College of Art and Design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Career guidance service for students</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/mathplus"/>
   <updated>2012-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/mathplus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mathplus&lt;/em&gt; is a concept service which helps math-inclined students identify potential career paths in high school. It aims to assist students in the job market by introducing them to successful professionals, practical applications for their skills, and example career paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h6&gt;Challenge&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Students struggle to connect skills and interests to careers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Design Research&lt;/em&gt; course gave us an open brief which asked we &amp;ldquo;identify a target audience in need and design a service to help them.&amp;rdquo; Working from personal experience, our group rallied around the challenges of students finding career paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;U.S. high schools average 1 guidance counsellor for every 450 students&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Process&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Narrow the target to focus on the problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key point in our process was choosing math-inclined students as our audience. After struggling to &amp;ldquo;solve careers for [all] students,&amp;rdquo; we found that focusing on a more narrow audenience enabled us to identify individual needs and specific use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Solution&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Connect students &amp;amp; professionals around relevant topics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mathplus-diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our focus helped us realize that the real disconnect is in how academic skills are applied to the &amp;ldquo;real world.&amp;rdquo; Students are taught in theory, concepts, and experiments, but rarely in direct applications. We saw a service being able to connect the dots between skills and career paths. These connections would be reinforced by active industry professionals who could publish content and consult directly with students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;video&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://player.vimeo.com/video/33514687?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=3a92c9&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;center-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cta&quot; title=&quot;Gather Degree Project Process Book&quot; href=&quot;http://issuu.com/willmillar/docs/mathplus&quot;&gt;Process book on Issuu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This service was developed as a concept for Brian Lucid&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Design Research&lt;/em&gt; course at Massachusetts College of Art and Design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Various motion graphics</title>
   <link href="http://willmillar.com/motion-graphics"/>
   <updated>2012-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://willmillar.com/motion-graphics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Motion has been an important part of my design process going back to my start in TV production in high school where I learned motion design in After Effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h6&gt;Freelance outreach marketing&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;MassArt Graphic Design promotion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We Are Thinkers And Makers&lt;/em&gt; is a 2012 promotional video for the MassArt Graphic Design program. Classmate Pat Bitchell and I were contracted to design a presentation for an outreach tour to design programs abroad. Our approach featured student interviews and project examples to showcase the talent, community, and resources of MassArt Graphic Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;video&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://player.vimeo.com/video/37980364?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=3a92c9&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h6&gt;Identify &amp;amp; motion graphics&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;SENSE network branding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SENSE&lt;/em&gt; is a concept TV network I branded in a 2012 project for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maviyane.com/&quot;&gt;Chaz Maviyane-Davies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Graphic Design&lt;/em&gt; course at MassArt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;video&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://player.vimeo.com/video/37973232?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=3a92c9&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h6&gt;Expressive motion typography&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ratatat&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Loud Pipes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Loud Pipes&amp;rdquo; is a 2011 motion typography study for &lt;a href=&quot;http://khughesdesign.com/&quot;&gt;Katherine Hughes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Typography&lt;/em&gt; course at MassArt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;video&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://player.vimeo.com/video/11567969?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=3a92c9&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h6&gt;Freelance outreach marketing&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Rap I Listen To&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I inventoried and analyzed the hip hop music I listened to, I noticed geographical groupings of lyrical themes. What happens when you take this kind of data-driven pattern identification too far? &amp;ldquo;The Rap I Listen To&amp;rdquo; is a 2011 video component to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianlucid.com/&quot;&gt;Brian Lucid&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Collection of 100 Items&amp;rdquo; project for &lt;em&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/em&gt; at MassArt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;video&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://player.vimeo.com/video/17792348
?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=3a92c9&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
